A Guide to the Virginia Alliance of Arts Education records, 1974-1989
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Alliance of Arts Education records, 1974-1989
The Library of Virginia
33089
.675 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
Virginia Alliance of Arts Education
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lena Long, secretary, and Jan Jones, president of the Virginia Alliance for Arts Education.
Custodial History
Accessions 33114 and 33659 are filed with accession 33089.
Historical Information
The Virginia Alliance for Arts Education (VAAE) was established in 1974 with help from the Commission of the Arts and Humanities and was incorporated 6 February 1976. The VAAE describes itself as "a non-profit statewide organization founded and maintained under federal authority as a State Committee of the Alliance for Arts Education. The principal commitment of the VAAE is to integrate and interweave all of the arts into the education experience of the citizens of the Commonwealth. Its membership is open to all educators, artists, interested individuals, arts organizations, and all professional organizations which represent or serve as advocates for all aspects of the educational process." It was part of the national Alliance for Arts Education at the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in Washington DC.
Scope and Content
Records, 1974-1989, of the Virginia Alliance for Arts Education consisting of correspondence, minutes, by-laws, articles of incorporation, membership lists, chapter formation records, arts awards criteria, papers concerning fine arts education in high schools, grant requests and announcements, final reports, newsletters, and conference programs concerning the goals and operation of the alliance to promote arts education in Virginia.
Contents List
- Correspondence of importance, 1975-1976, 1981-1987. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes--executive board, 1976-1982. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes--executive board, 1983-1984. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes--executive board, 1985. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes--executive board, 1986. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes--executive board, 1987-1989. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- By-laws and articles of incorporation, 1976, 1980-1983, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Financing requests, announcements, 1982-1987. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Final reports, 1981-1985, 1987. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Grant requests, 1977, 1983-1986. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Three-year plan, 1987. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Membership lists, 1983-1986. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Formation of chapters, 1983-1987. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arts award criteria outlined, 1981, 1983, 1985-1987, no date. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fine arts unit as high school graduation requirement, 1985-1986. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- newsletters, including Communique, 1975-1976, 1982-1986. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Programs and other papers for conferences, 1974, 1976-1977, 1982-1984. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Programs and other papers for conferences, 1985. (Box 2, Folder 8)